# MATT BABER

mbaber1142@gmail.com | 440.391.2637 | linkedin.com/in/matt-baber-68b9711b3/

GitHub: github.com/BaberMatt | Portfolio: babermatt.github.io/updatedPortfolio/

# **Technical Skills**

Languages: HTML5, CSS, MySQL/Mongo, JavaScript, NodeJS, Express, React

### **Applications:**

Git Products, SQL Workbench, MongoDB Compass, Postman, Heroku

### Summary

Full stack web developer that can find a kitchen analogy in any coding process or problem. Instilled with sense of urgency, curiosity, and commitment to quality through background as a fine dining chef. Analytical, systemsfocused approach and experience with diverse team dynamics.

# **Strengths**

Clear communication in complex projects with multiple stakeholders

Adherence to deadlines and management of time

Level-headedness in stressful & energetic situations

# **Projects**

Loaded | Logistical platform for tracking shipments https://github.com/baberMatt/loaded | https://loadedtruckingapp.herokuapp.com/

- Full-stack web app that allows users to input drivers & loads to a database & track the status of each load. A search page fetches filtered data points. Uses data-flagging to handle how loads are sorted & rendered out of database, & Google Maps API to display routes. Handlebars templating engine renders component partials.
- Initialized file structure & server, managed GitHub branching & merging, & generated all front-end JavaScript.
- Languages: JavaScript [Node, Express], MySQL, Handlebars, HTML/CSS

# streamLine | A front-end only application to help find livestreams and livestreamers https://github.com/baberMatt/StreamerSearch

- Front-end only application designed to help find live streams of games or find livestreamers by name. Utilizes YouTube API to compare search & fetch top rated stream & display to page with iframe.
- Initialized file structure, managed GitHub branching & merging, generated all front-end JavaScript, & edited final CSS.
- Languages: JavaScript [jQuery], HTML/CSS

# Turnup | A pop up event coordinator In development; links coming soon

- Developed using MERN stack, this app hosts listings for pop-up events & has the capabilities to track RSVPs, process attendee registrations, & connect to payment portals for ticketing & item preorders.
- Implemented MERN stack structure with focus on React client; ideated project concept, features, & theme.
- Languages: JavaScript [React, JSX, Express, Node], MongoDB, HTML/CSS

# MATT BABER

mbaber1142@gmail.com | 440.391.2637 | linkedin.com/in/matt-baber-68b9711b3/

GitHub: github.com/BaberMatt | Portfolio: babermatt.github.io/updatedPortfolio/

### **Education**

#### **Bootcamp Certificate**

February 2021 | Case Western Reserve University

#### **Culinary Arts Diploma**

May 2008 | International Culinary Arts & Science Institute

### Wild Mushroom Expert Certificate

March 2019 | Michigan Dept. of Agriculture & Rural Development

#### Permaculture Design Certificate

September 2016 | Midwest Permaculture

### **Interests**

Wild foods foraging & cultivation

Permaculture & sustainable agriculture
techniques

Fermentation

Hiking

Reading

Maps

# **Experience**

Chef, Farm Liaison & Larder Master 2015 – 2019 Spice Hospitality Group: Cleveland, OH

Trained & managed staff on proprietary techniques. Drew formulas, yields, & projections & kept dynamic inventory to streamline production. Managed communication between farm & chefs to maximize utilization of weekly harvest.

- Launched retail product line that strategically utilized food product to reduce waste.
- Developed modular event setup system that reduced labor hours for offsite events.
- Increased guest satisfaction for signature dinner series through menu ideation & execution.

Owner 2013 – 2016

Wolf Boy Provisions: Cleveland, OH

Owned & managed small business offering handmade, naturally cured meat products with commitment to local & ethical sourcing.

- Built highly marketable brand & product line within an in-demand niche.
- Navigated local, state & federal regulations to scale up & introduce efficiencies in production.

Executive Chef & Catering Chef 2010 – 2013

The Katz Club Diner & fire food & drink: Cleveland, OH

Managed staff & diverse production schedule for highend catered events & new restaurant concept.

- Led design process for new catering production kitchen to streamline movement of product & reduce labor hours.
- Managed large, high-end catered events with complex logistical considerations & challenges.
- Hired, trained, & supervised staff of 12.